<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David R. Hill on David R. Hill</title>
    <link>https://hilldr.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in David R. Hill on David R. Hill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Three lessons for the road ahead</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/post/teaching/end_of_year_advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/post/teaching/end_of_year_advice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last winter I served as course director for Clinical Immunology at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emich.edu/chhs/hs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eastern Michigan University&amp;rsquo;s School of Health Sciences&lt;/a&gt;. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve had some experience assisting with both undergraduate and graduate level courses in the past, this was my first experience as the course director and sole instructor for a college-level course. The whole process was exciting, challenging, and, ultimately, personally rewarding. It reinforced my long-standing enthusiasm for teaching and led to a number of important insights for me personally and professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reached the end of the semester I reflected back on what advice I might like to pass on to the students in my class before sending them on their way. Smashed in there at the tail end of a final lecture on vaccines and public health policy, I shared a single slide and a few remarks as a way of saying &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Thanks and Good Luck&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that this is not intended as some kind of all-encompassing life philosophy or guide&amp;hellip; just three bits of personal insight for the road ahead to take or leave as you please. So here goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take pride in your work.&lt;/strong&gt; Even many years into his retirement, my grandfather worked everyday. I remember helping him clean up in the yard. He would pile up all the fallen limbs and sticks and then cut them into lengths of exactly one foot, sort them by diameter, and then arrange them into equal bundles tied up with twine. Similarly, cardboard scraps from the house would be cut into squares, stacked, and tied up with twine before going out on the tree lawn for recycling collection. As a kid I thought, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Why would he waste all his time on that? Why not just throw it all in a bag like everybody else?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Many years later the meaning of his efforts dawned on me: not every task is interesting or exciting or fun. But when you take pride in your work, even the most menial task, you give it significance.  Whether it be gathering twigs in the yard or cleaning test tubes in your first research position, a job well done is a small gesture through which we say to ourselves and to others &lt;em&gt;I care&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hold the door open for others.&lt;/strong&gt; Michelle Obama said it best : &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;[W]hen you&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard, and done well, and walked through that doorway of opportunity, you do not slam it shut behind you. You reach back and you give other folks the same chances that helped you succeed.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; This is especially true in academia. If you&amp;rsquo;re here it&amp;rsquo;s because you have enjoyed some special privileges in life. The ability to get an education, perhaps connections to others in academia, or maybe just somebody who told you &lt;em&gt;that you had it in you to do this&lt;/em&gt;. As you move up through academic life, others will come to you looking for help. Take a moment to pass on some words of encouragement. Of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve done in my career, I&amp;rsquo;m most proud of the small roles I&amp;rsquo;ve played in others&amp;rsquo; successes - students who got into Medical or Graduate school, who got scholarships or grants, or who found a job. These moments make it all worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The future is uncertain; Trust that you will be able to figure it out when you get there.&lt;/strong&gt; Although it remains a popular line of questioning in job interviews and admissions processes, none of us knows where we are going to be in 5-10 years time. You can make the most comprehensive of plans, map out every aspect of your life and put all your various ducks in a perfect row and &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; many of the factors that determine whether those plans ultimately become reality will remain outside of your control. Uncertainty about the future is a big part of life in academia, where we sink or swim based on the whims of anonymous reviewers. But you&amp;rsquo;re a survivor. You&amp;rsquo;ve gone through who knows what to get where you are today. When challenges came, you figured it out. Or maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t. Maybe you really screwed up somewhere. You are human; failing at stuff is part of the deal. But whatever happened, you got here. And you can do it again. And again. And again&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A System for Reproducible Research</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/project/reproducible_research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/project/reproducible_research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fundamental assumption that serves as the philosophical engine of modern science is that the phenomena we observe and measure in the lab are representative of universal phenomena. Intestinal epithelial cells in the lab express antimicrobial peptides when provoked because presumably this response is a property of all intestinal epithelial cells. Or, taking a more classical example, a feather and a cannonball fall to the earth at the same rate in a vacuum because acceleration due to gravity acts on them equally. For science to be useful these observations must be true &lt;em&gt;in every case where identical conditions are present&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replicating experimental conditions exactly has always been difficult. The problem is particularly significant in the biomedical sciences where the conditions to replicate an experiment may require specialized skills, equipment, and reagents. And in many cases the experimental conditions may not be well defined, or may not be completely definable within the current limitations of our understanding. Consider the complexity of a single bacterial cell: even &lt;em&gt;E. coli/&lt;/em&gt; K-12, perhaps the single best characterized organism known to science, behaves in ways that do not fit our current understanding or predictions. This type of failure of reproducibility is intrinsic to science; we simply don&amp;rsquo;t know what we don&amp;rsquo;t know. Early attempts at skin grafts were widely variable, with some surgeons publishing anecdotal reports of complete success and others reporting the miserable failure of these techniques. At the time, the HLA system was entirely unknown and the notion that we might match donor and recipient tissues according to some biological criteria didn&amp;rsquo;t exist. The contrast between successful skin grants and failed skin grafts and the investigations that followed eventually resulted in the HLA tissue typing system that has enabled modern tissue transplant procedures and has by now saved many thousands of lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second and more commonplace challenge to reproducibility are simple lapses in our technique: memories fail, training quality varies, files get deleted and notebooks get lost. People drop test tubes, knock over the Bunsen burner, contaminate the cell culture, and just generally behave like the imperfect beings we always will be. The solutions here are as simple as the explanations: keep better documentation and try again until you get it right. Well&amp;hellip; simple in concept, if not in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A third challenge to reproducibility is more insidious. Many scientific observations are subject to a certain degree of interpretation. Two reasonable scientists can disagree on the best statistical test for a given hypothesis. One scientist may think that removal of certain samples from analysis is justified while another may disagree. On their own these kinds of debates are not harmful. Things get complicated of course when we consider the potential for conflicts of interest between the interpretation of scientific results and the prospects for career-making publications and grant applications. The unfortunate truth is that our scientific results are not entirely independent of our career trajectory, despite good science demanding that the experimental design and interpretation be independent of personal and political concerns. Many solutions have been proposed to this conundrum over the years, and there are many broad scale changes to our system that I would personally support but will not elaborate on here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, my aims are more localized. For the past several years I have invested time and effort in developing a workflow for documenting my experiments and data analysis in a system that allows anyone to generate the same results from the raw data files and to follow my explicit rationale, as documented in computer code, for every step of the process. This series of blog posts will address my efforts to tackle reproducibility in my own work by producing &lt;strong&gt;better and more accessible documentation of methods&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;maximum transparency in data analysis&lt;/strong&gt;. My hope is that these posts can serve as a teaching resource for members of my research team and the larger community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Neonatal Microbial Colonization in Human Intestinal Organoids</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/project/hios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/project/hios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All multicellular organisms have a problem: surviving in a world that is already fully occupied by bacteria and other single celled organisms. We call this problem &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symbiosis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;symbiosis&lt;/a&gt;. The primary solution to this problem is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutualism_(biology)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mutualism&lt;/a&gt;, which intimately links the survival of individual organisms and as a result has shaped the evolution of both bacterial and multicellular life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interplay is central to the maturation and function of the human gastrointestinal tract. Our guts are colonized by mutualistic and other bacteria at birth. These bacteria come from a variety of sources, including our moms and other family members, our environment, and the things we eat early in life. Once these bacteria arrive in our guts, some of them grow rapidly and begin to form dense communities with increasing abilities to help us process the food we eat, regulate our immune response, and many other functions that we have recently begun to understand. At the same time, our intestines are maturing rapidly by generating digestive cells, secreting protective mucus and antimicrobial compounds, and formulating adaptive immune protections that will affect us for the rest of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interplay between microbial colonization and expansion in the gut and the development of the gut itself has been difficult to study. There are no germ-free human research subjects. In my research I apply &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature09691&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;innovate cell culture model systems&lt;/a&gt; that allow us to grow germ-free human intestinal tissue in the lab. &lt;a href=&#34;https://elifesciences.org/articles/29132&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Our work&lt;/a&gt; has shown that these tissues can sustain symbiosis with mutualistic bacteria and that this relationship kickstarts maturation of the lining of the human intestine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently using this system to explore the factors that contribute to the failure of the intestinal maturation in some premature infants. Identification of specific conditions that determine the success or failure of intestinal maturation following bacterial colonization may lead to treatments for devastating conditions such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://necsociety.org/nec-now/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;necrotizing enterocolitis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of host-microbial interaction networks that mediate intestinal epithelial barrier maturation</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/talk/2018_gi/2018_gi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/talk/2018_gi/2018_gi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification, isolation and characterization of human LGR5-positive colon adenoma cells.</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2018-01-01_dame2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2018-01-01_dame2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Vitro Induction and In Vivo Engraftment of Lung Bud Tip Progenitor Cells Derived from Human Pluripotent Stem Cells.</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2018-01-01_miller2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2018-01-01_miller2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Measurement of Epithelial Barrier Permeability in Human Intestinal Organoids</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/jove_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/jove_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial colonization stimulates a complex physiological response in the immature human intestinal epithelium</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/elife_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/elife_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gastrointestinal Organoids: Understanding the Molecular Basis of the Host–Microbe Interface</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/cmgh_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/cmgh_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial colonization stimulates a complex physiological response in the immature human intestinal epithelium.</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_hill2017a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_hill2017a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gastrointestinal Organoids: Understanding the Molecular Basis of the Host-Microbe Interface.</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_hill2017b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_hill2017b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphogenesis and maturation of the embryonic and postnatal intestine.</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_chin2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_chin2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Measurement of Epithelial Barrier Permeability in Human Intestinal Organoids.</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_hill2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/publication/my-md-folder/2017-01-01_hill2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time measurement of epithelial barrier permeability in human intestinal organoids</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/project/hio-microinjection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/project/hio-microinjection/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
