<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David R. Hill</title>
    <link>https://hilldr.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David R. Hill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hilldr.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Three lessons for the road ahead</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/post/teaching/end_of_year_advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/post/teaching/end_of_year_advice/</guid>
      <description>Last winter I served as course director for Clinical Immunology at Eastern Michigan University&amp;rsquo;s School of Health Sciences. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve had some experience assisting with both undergraduate and graduate level courses in the past, this was my first experience as the course director and sole instructor for a college-level course. The whole process was exciting, challenging, and, ultimately, personally rewarding. It reinforced my long-standing enthusiasm for teaching and led to a number of important insights for me personally and professionally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutual understanding: uncovering the mechanistic basis of the host-symbiont relationship in human health</title>
      <link>https://hilldr.github.io/post/org-mode-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hilldr.github.io/post/org-mode-blogging/</guid>
      <description>This article was first published here. You can also read a Q&amp;A I did with the Lasker Foundation in 2016 here.
Although rotation of the earth around the sun was first proposed by Copernicus, it took Galileo&#39;s telescope and Newton&#39;s laws of gravitation to demonstrate that heliocentric theory was irrefutably true. Likewise, although Darwin proposed natural selection as the means by which species originated and demonstrated that the natural world was consistent with this hypothesis, the work of Watson, Crick, and Wilkins elucidated the biochemical foundation of trait inheritance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>